Register of the Josef Škvorecký Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Josef Škvorecký papers
1908-1994
91008
Škvorecký, Josef.
79 manuscript boxes 32.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Czech and world literature, Czech culture, political and social conditions in Czechoslovakia, and Czech émigré life.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1924 September 27 Born, Náchod, Czechoslovakia
1951 PhD, Charles University, Prague
1956 Deputy editor-in-chief, World Literature Today
1958 Married Zdenka Josefa Salivarová
1969 Emigrated to Canada and founded Sixty-Eight Publishers for independent Czech literature
1973- Lecturer, Voice of America
1975-1990 Professor of English, University of Toronto, Ontario
1977 Author, Samožerbuch
1980 Received Neustadt Prize for Literature, University of Oklahoma
1984 Author, Scherzo capriccioso (Dvořák in Love)
1985 Received Canadian Governor General's Award
1990 Received Order of the White Lion Received literature prize, Echoing Green Foundation Advisor to Václav Havel, president of Czechoslovakia and the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic
1999 Received Czech Republic's State Prize for Literature
2001 Received Dangea prize
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Literature; Czech literature.; Czechs in foreign countries.; Czechoslovakia--Civilization.; Czechoslovakia--Intellectual life.
Collection Contents
- Biographical File, 1934-1994. (Box 1)
  File on Skvorecký's birthplace
  - File on Náchod a Hořice (Skvorecký's birthplace), 1950, 1970-1994 (Folder 1: 1-3)
    Brochures, drawings, letters from residents, and poems
- Writings, 1967-1994. (Box 2-12)
  Research materials and letters from readers, arranged chronologically by title
  - Samožerbuch (Panorama, 1977, 1991). Research materials and letters from readers, 1967-1994 (Folder 2: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 3: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 4: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 5: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 6: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 7: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 8: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 9: 1-4)
  - Samožerbuch (Contd.) (Folder 10: 1-4)
  - Scherzo capriccioso (Dvořák novel) (Sixty-Eight Publishers, 1983). Research materials and letters from readers, 1980-1990 (Folder 11: 1-4)
  - Scherzo capriccioso (Dvořák novel) (Sixty-Eight Publishers, 1983). Research materials and letters from readers, 1990-1993 (Folder 12: 1-3)
- Correspondence, 1919-1994. (Box 13-72)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    - General
      - General
        - Anecdotes (Anekdoty), 1978 (Folder 13: 1)
        - Anonymous letters from Prague (Anonymové z Prahy), 1968, 1978-1982 (Folder 13: 2)
        - Book reviews, critiques, clippings (recese, kritiky, články o československé kultuře), 1969-1974 (Folder 13: 3-4)
        - Clippings about
          - Immigration, 1968 (Folder 13: 5-6)
          - New publications of Sixty-Eight Publishers, 1969-1975
        - Letters by admirers, 1970-1977 (Folder 13: 7)
        - Letters of recommendation, 1986-1989 (Folder 14: 1)
        - Requests for translation and publication (Nabídky a žádosťi, nabídky různých autorů a překladatelů), 1983-1989 (Folder 14: 2-4)
        - Requests for translation and publication (Nabídky a žádosťi, nabídky různých autorů a překladatelů), 1983-1993 (Folder 15: 1-4)
        - Miscellany, 1980-1992 (Folder 15: 5)
      - American universities, 1971-1977 (Folder 16: 1)
      - Author dictionary (Slovník spisovatelů), 1977-1983 (Folder 16: 2-3)
      - Authors of manuscripts (Autoři různých rukopisů), 1979-1984 (Folder 16: 4-5)
      - Competing publishers, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Painters (Malíři), 1989-1992 (Folder 17: 2)
      - Poets (Básníci), 1980 (Folder 17: 3)
      - Signatories of the Charta 77 (Chartisti), 1978-1983 (Folder 17: 4)
      - Slang dictionary (Slovník slangu), 1979 (Folder 17: 5)
      - Surrealist artists (Surrealisti), 1980-1984 (Folder 17: 6)
      - Translators (Překladatelé), 1980-1984 (Folder 17: 7)
    - A-C (Folder 17: 8)
    - D-F (Folder 17: 9)
    - G-I (Folder 17: 10)
    - J-L (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - M-O (Folder 18: 2)
    - P-R (Folder 18: 3)
    - S (Folder 18: 4)
    - T-V (Folder 18: 5)
    - W-Z (Folder 18: 6)
  - Unidentified
    - General, 1970-1973 (Folder 18: 7)
    - Brian, 1973 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Honza, 1973 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Jait, 1973 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Jana, n.d. (Folder 19: 4)
    - Jiří, 1973 (Folder 19: 5)
    - Jirka, n.d. (Folder 19: 6)
    - Joida, 1971 (Folder 19: 7)
    - Karel, 1971 (Folder 19: 8)
    - Kathryn, 1982 (Folder 19: 9)
    - Květa, 1971-1973 (Folder 19: 10)
    - Majkl, 1973 (Folder 19: 11)
    - Paul, 1971 (Folder 19: 12)
    - Vašek, n.d. (Folder 19: 13)
    - Věra, n.d. (Folder 19: 14)
    - Vilma, 1973 (Folder 19: 15)
    - Vladimír, 1971 (Folder 19: 16)
    - Zuzinka, 1971 (Folder 19: 17)
  - Adamík, Miloslav, 1981-1983 (Folder 19: 18)
  - Adams, Pepper, 1987 (Folder 19: 19)
  - Adler, Petr, 1990-1993 (Folder 19: 20)
  - Amis, Kingsley, 1980-1992 (Folder 19: 21)
  - Ancelot, Claudia, 1980-1987 (Folder 19: 22)
  - Anderman, Janusz, 1983 (Folder 19: 23)
  - Aškenázy, Ludvik, 1983 (Folder 19: 24)
  - Auský, Stanislav A., 1977-1991 (Folder 19: 25)
  - Baarová, Lída, 1977-1990 (Folder 19: 26-27)
  - Baluch, Jacek, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Bambásková, Marie, 1978-1981 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Bára, 1983 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Baran, Dušan, 1979-1980 (Folder 20: 4)
  - Barber, Amy Lynn, 1993 (Folder 20: 5)
  - Barbier, Eva, 1987-1988 (Folder 20: 6)
  - Barborka, Emma P., 1981-1994 (Folder 20: 7-8)
  - Bartoš, Antonín, 1980 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Bartošek, Karel, 1983-1990 (Folder 20: 10)
  - Bartošová, Vlasta, 1980 (Folder 20: 11)
  - Basora, Pauline Barnes, 1992-1993 (Folder 20: 12)
  - Batchelor, John Calvin, 1989 (Folder 20: 13)
  - Bednář, Jan, 1981 (Folder 20: 14)
  - Beer, Olinka Nesvadba, 1980 (Folder 20: 15)
  - Běhounek, Kamil, 1935-1988 (Folder 20: 16)
  - Bell, Graeme, 1993 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Bellow, Saul, 1989 (Folder 21: 2)
  - Bénamou, Geneviève, 1980-1981 (Folder 21: 3)
  - Beneš, Jan, 1971-1994 (Folder 21: 4-6)
  - Benešová, Irena, n.d. (Folder 21: 7)
  - Benýšek, Zbyněk, 1985-1988 (Folder 21: 8)
  - Beranová, Jana, 1980 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Berger, Thomas, 1972, 1987 (Folder 21: 10)
  - Berton, Stanislav, 1980-1992 (Folder 21: 11)
  - Binar, Ivan, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Bitter Verlag, 1978 (Folder 22: 2)
  - Bittman, Ladislav, 1976-1983 (Folder 22: 3)
  - Bittová, Iva, 1991 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Blatný, Ivan, 1977-1994 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Blažek, Vladimír, 1979-1981 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Blažek, Vratislav and Hana, 1970-1984 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Blažížek, Přemysl, 1993-1994 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Blažková, Járinka, 1979-1982 (Folder 22: 9)
  - Blekastad, Milada, 1980-1990 (Folder 22: 10)
  - Bondy, Egon, 1978-1985, 1993 (Folder 22: 11)
  - Bondy, Jindřich, 1981-1982 (Folder 22: 12)
  - Boreš, Jiří, 1979 (Folder 22: 13)
  - Borský, Jiří, 1980 (Folder 22: 14)
  - Bošek, Pavel, 1980 (Folder 22: 15)
  - Bouček, Zdeněk, 1989 (Folder 23: 1)
  - Bradáčová, Alena, 1984 (Folder 23: 2)
  - Bradbury, Ray, 1974-1992 (Folder 23: 3)
  - Bradley, John, 1981 (Folder 23: 4)
  - Bradová, Zuzana, 1980 (Folder 23: 5)
  - Brázdová, Valerie, 1979-1990 (Folder 23: 6)
  - Brčková, Jana, 1981 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Brdečka, Jiří, 1949-1981 (Folder 23: 8)
  - Bristol, Barbara, 1983-1994 (Folder 23: 9-10)
  - Brod, Petr, 1981 (Folder 23: 11)
  - Brodská, Zdenka, 1981 (Folder 23: 12)
  - Brooks, 1991 (Folder 23: 13)
  - Brousek, Antonín, 1971-1994 (Folder 23: 14-15)
  - Brychta, Lída and Jan, 1971-1993 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Brychtová, Lenka, 1979-1980 (Folder 24: 2)
  - Brzorád, Vilém, 1971, 1987-1991 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Buber-Neumann, Margarete, 1979-1986 (Folder 24: 4)
  - Budík, Arnošt, 1973-1976 (Folder 24: 5)
  - Burr, John, 1989-1991 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Čačalová, Libuše, 1986 (Folder 24: 7)
  - Callenbach, Ernest, 1983 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Čamrda, Zdeněk, 1971, 1981-1982, 1993-1994 (Folder 24: 9)
  - Canadian Writers Association, 1984 (Folder 24: 10)
  - Čech, Sláva, 1987 (Folder 24: 11)
  - Cekota, Anthony, 1980-1983 (Folder 24: 12)
  - Celba, Jaroslav, 1990 (Folder 24: 13)
  - Černý, Jiří, 1971-1982 (Folder 24: 14)
  - Černý, Václav, 1966-1991 (Folder 24: 15-16)
  - Čeřovský, Zbyněk, 1980-1984 (Folder 24: 17)
  - Červená, Soňa, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Červinka, František, 1978-1986 (Folder 25: 2)
  - Chadim, Václav, 1990-1993 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Chalupecký, Jindřich, 1983 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Charles, Veronika, 1979-1992 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Chudožilov, Petr, 1982-1991 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Chvatík, Květoslav, 1980-1994 (Folder 25: 7-8)
  - Chytilová, Věra, 1988 (Folder 25: 9)
  - Cibulka, Frank, 1993 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Cícha, Vladimír, 1989 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Čolič, Milan, 1987 (Folder 25: 12)
  - Čulík, Jan, 1984-1992 (Folder 25: 13-14)
  - Davies, Robertson, 1984 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Dědeček, Jiří, 1990-1994 (Folder 26: 2)
  - Dienstbier, Jiří, 1986-1987 (Folder 26: 3)
  - Disher, Hanyi, 1973-1978 (Folder 26: 4)
  - Divia, Ivan, 1971-1990 (Folder 26: 5)
  - Dohnal, Dan, 1973-1987 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Dorůžka, Lubomídr, 1971-1994 (Folder 26: 7-9)
  - Dorůžka, Lubomír, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 27: 1-3)
  - Doupovec, Radomír, 1980 (Folder 27: 4)
  - Doyle, Noel J., Jr., 1987 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Drábek, Jan, 1971-1994 (Folder 27: 6-7)
  - Drahovoupilová, Madla, 1981-1986 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Drašnar, Jiří, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Dresler, Jaroslav, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Drozd, Karel, 1980-1993. (Folder 28: 2)
  - Drtina, Richard, 1978-1985. (Folder 28: 3)
  - Dubská-Mlynářová, Irena, 1978-1981. (Folder 28: 4)
  - Duffel, Peter, 1986-1993. (Folder 28: 5)
  - Durych, Václav, 1984-1990. (Folder 28: 6)
  - Ebels-Dolanová, Věra, 1971, 1993-1994. (Folder 28: 7)
  - Edice Petlice, 1978. (Folder 28: 8)
  - Effenberger, V., 1980. (Folder 28: 9)
  - Eichler, Václav, 1979-1982. (Folder 28: 10)
  - Eichlerová, Ladislava, 1991. (Folder 28: 11)
  - Elefteriadu, Tena, 1980-1987 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Elznic, Lukáš, 1984-1991. (Folder 28: 13)
  - Emmer, Jarmila and Jan, 1980-1994. (Folder 28: 14)
  - Enzensberger, Hans Magnus, 1986. (Folder 28: 15)
  - Feuer, Kathryn, 1980-1988. (Folder 28: 16)
  - Fibírová, Járinka, 1987-1993 (Folder 28: 17)
  - Fic, Victor M., 1988. (Folder 28: 18)
  - Filip, Ota, 1972-1993. (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Fiš, Teodor, 1979-1980. (Folder 29: 2)
  - Fischl, Victor, 1977-1988 (Folder 29: 3)
  - Fleischer, Vladimír, 1979-1982 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Fleischmann, Michel, 1981 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Fodor, Jiří and Jindra, 1971, 1981-1994 (Folder 29: 6-7)
  - Folke, Patrick V., 1984-1988 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Forman, Miloš, 1979-1994 (Folder 29: 9)
  - Franěk, Jirka, 1980 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Frankfurtský kurýr, 1971-1972 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Frei, Bohumil, 1992 (Folder 30: 3)
  - French, Alfred, 1971-1985 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Frýbert, Tomáš, 1979 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Fuks, Ladislav, 1990 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Gal, T., 1982, 1991 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Galan, František, 1981-1991 (Folder 30: 8)
  - Galligan, Edward L., 1993 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Gatenby, Greg, 1984 (Folder 30: 10)
  - Geifman, 1991 (Folder 30: 11)
  - Gerová, Irena, 1989 (Folder 30: 12)
  - Gibian, Jirka, 1980-1991 (Folder 30: 13)
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1981-1994 (Folder 30: 14)
  - Goldscheider, František, 1982-1990 (Folder 30: 15)
  - Goldstuecker, Eduard, 1970, 1981 (Folder 30: 16)
  - Gott, Karel, 1971 (Folder 30: 17)
  - Greene, Graham, 1968-1992 (Folder 30: 18)
  - Greenwald, 1981 (Folder 30: 19)
  - Greig, Eva, 1983 (Folder 30: 20)
  - Grosman, Ladislav, 1971-1980 (Folder 30: 21)
  - Grove Press, 1987 (Folder 30: 22)
  - Gruša, Jiří, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 31: 1-2)
  - Guderna, Ladislav, n.d. (Folder 31: 3)
  - Habr, Miloň, 1980-1983 (Folder 31: 4)
  - Hájek, Igor, 1970-1999 (Folder 31: 5-8)
  - Hájek, Igor, 1970-1999 (Box-folder 32: 1-7)
  - Halla, Milan J., 1984-1985 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Halsey, Zuzana, 1988 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Hammer, Milan, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Hammond, John, 1979-1981 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Hampl, Patricia, 1981-1982 (Folder 33: 3)
  - Hankó, Ludmila, 1989-1990 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Hanuš, Miroslav, 1984-1985 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Hanzálek, Jiří, 1983-1988 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Hanzlicek, Charles, 1986-1990 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Hanzlík, Richard, 1971-1983 (Folder 33: 8)
  - Harníček, Martin, 1979-1985 (Folder 33: 9)
  - Harnick, Michaela, 1989-1992 (Folder 33: 10)
  - Hauková, Jiřina, 1984-1985 (Folder 33: 11)
  - Hauner, Milan, 1986 (Folder 33: 12)
  - Havel, Václav, 1971-1979 (Folder 33: 13-18)
  - Havel, Václav, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 34: 1-14)
  - Havláček, Karel, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Havlínová, Alena, 1988-1989 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Heim, Michael, 1973-1986 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Hejl, Karola and Vilém, 1975-1989 (Folder 35: 4-5)
  - Heller, Viktor, 1993-1994 (Folder 35: 6)
  - Hercíková, Iva, 1986-1992 (Folder 35: 7)
  - Hiršal, Josef, 1986-1990 (Folder 35: 8)
  - Hladký, Ivan, 1993 (Folder 35: 9)
  - Hlas domova, 1971-1972 (Folder 35: 10)
  - Hochman, Jiří, 1974-1978 (Folder 35: 11)
  - Hodač, Jiří, 1984-1988 (Folder 35: 12)
  - Hodek, Antonín, 1980-1984 (Folder 35: 13)
  - Hoffman, Eva, 1992 (Folder 35: 14)
  - Holub, Miroslav, 1979 (Folder 36: 1)
  - Holub, Radovan, 1993 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Holubová, Miloslava, 1981-1984 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Hora, Karel, 1973-1981 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Hora, Ota, 1977-1988 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Horák, Antonín, 1971-1985 (Folder 36: 6)
  - Hořec, Jaromír, 1975-1994 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Hornychová, Ladislava, 1980-1991 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Hostovský, Egon, 1971-1992 (Folder 36: 9-11)
  - Hrabal, Bohumil, 1973-1993 (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
  - Hrádek, Dalibor, 1993 (Folder 37: 3)
  - Hruban, Zdeněk, 1981-1993 (Folder 37: 4)
  - Hrubín, Vít, 1982-1989 (Folder 37: 5)
  - Hrubý, Petr, 1983-1990 (Folder 37: 6)
  - Hutka, Jaroslav, 1978-1987 (Folder 37: 7)
  - Hvížďala, Karel, 1978-1994 (Folder 37: 8-9)
  - Idh, Ewa, 1985 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Ilič, Alexandr, 1981-1994 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Imhoff, Milena, 1980-1982 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Index Verlag, 1971-1989 (Folder 38: 4)
  - Ingris Productions, 1983 (Folder 38: 5)
  - International Association of Crime Writers, 1987-1993 (Folder 38: 6)
  - Istratová, Irina, 1991 (Folder 38: 7)
  - Ivak, Kateřina, 1991 (Folder 38: 8)
  - Ivanov, Miroslav, 1990 (Folder 38: 9)
  - Ivask, Astrid and Ivar, 1980-1993 (Folder 38: 10)
  - Iwachow, Miroslav, 1979 (Folder 38: 11)
  - Jadrný, Karel, 1980-1989 (Folder 38: 12)
  - Jaehn, Karl-Heinz, 1970-1973, 1990-1991 (Folder 38: 13)
  - Jagodzinski, Andrzej S., 1985-1990 (Folder 38: 14)
  - Janda, Bruce A., 1980 (Folder 38: 15)
  - Janeček, M., 1981 (Folder 38: 16)
  - Janko, Ivo, 1981-1987 (Folder 38: 17)
  - Janouch, František, 1981-1987 (Folder 38: 18)
  - Janouch, František, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Jánský, Radko K., 1980 (Folder 39: 2)
  - Janýr, Přemek, 1979 (Folder 39: 3)
  - Jařab, 1992 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Jasný, Vojtěch, 1978-1988 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Jazzová sekce svazu hudebníků ČSR, 1980-1987 (Folder 39: 6-8)
  - Jazzová sekce svazu hudebníků ČSR, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
  - Jedlička, Josef, 1971-1979 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Jehlička, Ladislav, 1987-1989 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Jelínek, Ivan, 1970-1989 (Folder 40: 5)
  - Jelínek, Milan, 1992 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Jelínek, Oldřich, 1982 (Folder 40: 7)
  - Jelinowicz, Martin, 1982-1983 (Folder 40: 8)
  - Jelus, Wanda, 1979-1980 (Folder 40: 9)
  - Jeřábek, Jaroslav, 1971, 1990-1992 (Folder 40: 10)
  - Jičínská, Blanka, 1977-1991 (Folder 40: 11)
  - Jirásek, Jan, 1971-1993 (Folder 40: 12-13)
  - Jirounek, Petr, 1984 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Jirous, Ivan M., 1985-1987 (Folder 41: 2)
  - Jirousek, Tomáš, 1982 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Johnsson, Alka, 1992-1993 (Folder 41: 4)
  - Jonášová, Lida, 1979-1980 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Jordan, Fred, 1993 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Julina, František, 1980 (Folder 41: 7)
  - Jungwirth, Franta, 1977-1992 (Folder 41: 8)
  - Just, Jiří and Vladimír, 1991 (Folder 41: 9)
  - Justl, Vladimír, 1989-1994 (Folder 41: 10-11)
  - Kabeš, Petr, 1979 (Folder 41: 12)
  - Kadlec, Petr, 1987 (Folder 41: 13)
  - Kalina, Ladislav Ján, 1978-1982 (Folder 41: 14)
  - Kalista, Zdeněk, 1975-1982 (Folder 41: 15)
  - Kalus, Milan, 1982-1984 (Folder 41: 16)
  - Káňa, Vašek, 1986-1988 (Folder 41: 17)
  - Kantůrková, Eva, 1979, 1987 (Folder 41: 18)
  - Kaplan, Karel, 1977-1994 (Folder 41: 19)
  - Karásek, Svatopluk, 1988 (Folder 41: 20)
  - Karbusický, Vladimír, 1983-1984 (Folder 41: 21)
  - Karfík, Vlastimil, 1982 (Folder 41: 22)
  - Karlovský, Adolf F. J., 1971-1993 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Kattan, n.d. (Folder 42: 2)
  - Kaválek, Luboš, 1979 (Folder 42: 3)
  - Kavan, Jan, 1973-1994 (Folder 42: 4-5)
  - Kejzlar, Radko, 1978-1985 (Folder 42: 6)
  - Kelly, Milena, 1992 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Kemr, Josef, 1991 (Folder 42: 8)
  - Kepka, Ondřej, 1993 (Folder 42: 9)
  - Khun, Miroslav, 1990-1993 (Folder 42: 10)
  - Kistlerová, Věra, 1983-1984 (Folder 42: 11)
  - Klanger, Zdeněk, 1980-1984 (Folder 42: 12)
  - Kleberg, Olof, 1981-1985 (Folder 42: 13)
  - Klíma, Ivan, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Klíma, Tomáš, 1981-1982 (Folder 43: 2)
  - Kliment, Alexandr, 1974-1991 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Klimea, Otto, 1983 (Folder 43: 4)
  - Klimesh, Cyril, 1984 (Folder 43: 5)
  - Klír, Jirka, 1988 (Folder 43: 6)
  - Klobouk, Jiří, 1980 (Folder 43: 7)
  - Knieža, Emil, 1971, 1982 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Knittl, Jaroslav, 1991-1992 (Folder 43: 9)
  - Koblasa, Jan, 1967-1981 (Folder 43: 10)
  - Koc, Helena, 1979-1980 (Folder 43: 11)
  - Kocourek, Milan, 1976-1989 (Folder 43: 12)
  - Koenigsmark, Josef, 1976 (Folder 43: 13)
  - Kohák, Erazim, 1970-1990 (Folder 43: 14-15)
  - Kohout, Jára, 1988 (Folder 44: 1)
  - Kohout, Pavel, 1974-1989 (Folder 44: 2-3)
  - Kohoutová, Kateřina, 1989-1990 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Koláček, 1984-1990 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Kolár, Jean, 1975-1983 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Kolář, Jiří, 1978-1992 (Folder 44: 7)
  - Kolman, Arnošt, 1976-1986 (Folder 44: 8)
  - Konopásek, Jan, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Konůpek, Michael, 1977-1989 (Folder 45: 2)
  - Kořán, Jaroslav, 1982-1991 (Folder 45: 3)
  - Koseková, Helena, 1971-1993 (Folder 45: 4)
  - Košťál, Arnošt, 1991 (Folder 45: 5)
  - Kotalík, J. F., n.d. (Folder 45: 6)
  - Kotas, Jiří, 1991-1993 (Folder 45: 7)
  - Kotrlí, Iva, 1984-1993 (Folder 45: 8)
  - Kouba, Petr, 1983-1991 (Folder 45: 9)
  - Kovályová, Heda, 1971-1988 (Folder 45: 10)
  - Kovanda, Karel, 1979 (Folder 45: 11)
  - Kovtun, Jiří, 1971-1992 (Folder 45: 12)
  - Kozel, George J., 1979-1980 (Folder 45: 13)
  - Krajina, Vladimír, 1977-1988 (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - Kríl, Petr, 1977-1992 (Folder 46: 2)
  - Kratochvil, Antonín, 1975-1992 (Folder 46: 3)
  - Kratošková, Světla, 1971-1972 (Folder 46: 4)
  - Kraus, Ivan, 1975 (Folder 46: 5)
  - Kraus, Otto B., 1971-1982 (Folder 46: 6)
  - Krause, Oskar, 1980-1986 (Folder 46: 7)
  - Krautgartner, Karel, 1982 (Folder 46: 8)
  - Krčil, Bohumil, 1979-1992 (Folder 46: 9)
  - Křen, Jan, 1984-1989 (Folder 46: 10)
  - Křesadlová, 1989 (Folder 46: 11)
  - Kriseová, Eda, 1978-1992 (Folder 46: 12-13)
  - Krištof, Václav, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 47: 1-3)
  - Kristofori, Jan, 1982-1987 (Folder 47: 4)
  - Křivánek, Lada, 1980 (Folder 47: 5)
  - Kříž, Vladimír, 1980-1993 (Folder 47: 6)
  - Kršič, Nikola, 1971 (Folder 47: 7)
  - Krumbachová, Ester, 1992-1993 (Folder 47: 8)
  - Krupička, Jiří, 1982-1989 (Folder 47: 9)
  - Kryl, Karel, 1976-1991 (Folder 47: 10)
  - Krystlik, Tomáš, 1989 (Folder 47: 11)
  - Kubešová, Blanka, 1980-1989 (Folder 47: 12)
  - Kubišová, Marta, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Kučera, C. R., 1979-1980 (Folder 48: 2)
  - Kučera, J., 1987 (Folder 48: 3)
  - Kučera, Oscar, 1986 (Folder 48: 4)
  - Kučerová, Stanislava, 1951, 1990 (Folder 48: 5)
  - Kudelková, Anna, 1984-1990 (Folder 48: 6)
  - Kulka, Erich, 1973-1985 (Folder 48: 7)
  - Kundera, Milan, 1971-1993 (Folder 48: 8-10)
  - Kunta, Miloš, 1976 (Folder 49: 1)
  - Kural, V., 1989-1990 (Folder 49: 2)
  - Kusák, Alexej, 1971 (Folder 49: 3)
  - Kusín, Vladimír, 1970-1984 (Folder 49: 4)
  - Kussi, Peter, 1972-1993 (Folder 49: 5)
  - Kyncl, Karel, 1984-1988 (Folder 49: 6)
  - Kypta, Míra, 1990-1993 (Folder 49: 7)
  - Kyška, Honza, 1983-1990 (Folder 49: 8)
  - Lamberg, Roberto F., 1977-1989 (Folder 49: 9)
  - Landovský, Pavel, 1979-1988 (Folder 49: 10)
  - Langerová, Daniela, 1984 (Folder 49: 11)
  - Laub, Gabriel, 1971 (Folder 49: 12)
  - Lecoque, 1975-1976 (Folder 49: 13)
  - Lederer, Jiří, 1980-1986 (Folder 49: 14)
  - Lee Yoke Har, n.d. (Folder 49: 15)
  - Lees, Gene, 1981-1982 (Folder 49: 16)
  - Lendl, Ivan, 1986 (Folder 49: 17)
  - Levertov, Denise, 1992 (Folder 49: 18)
  - Levy, Alan, 1971-1992 (Folder 49: 19)
  - Lexa, Hanuš, 1971 (Folder 49: 20)
  - Libal Barker, Mary, 1971, 1980 (Folder 49: 21)
  - Liehm, Antonín J., 1946, 1971-1990 (Folder 49: 22-23)
  - Límanová, Eva, 1986-1987 (Folder 49: 24)
  - Lindekrantz, Eva, 1984 (Folder 49: 25)
  - Linhartová, Věra, 1971-1980 (Folder 49: 26)
  - Lion, Jindřich, 1988 (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - Lípa, Jiří, 1981 (Folder 50: 2)
  - Loewy, Jiří, 1971, 1982-1987 (Folder 50: 3)
  - Lotar, Peter, 1978 (Folder 50: 4)
  - Ludvík, Emil, 1988-1993 (Folder 50: 5)
  - Lukas, Jan, 1987-1988 (Folder 50: 6)
  - Lukeš, Igor, 1978, 1988-1993 (Folder 50: 7)
  - Lustig, Arnošt, 1970-1993 (Folder 50: 8-9)
  - Luža, Radomír, 1980-1989 (Folder 50: 10)
  - Machann, Clinton, 1987-1993 (Folder 50: 11)
  - Machulková, Inka, 1981-1983 (Folder 50: 12)
  - Mandlová, Adina, 1973-1991 (Folder 50: 13)
  - Manyland Books, 1980 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Mára, Josef, 1991 (Folder 51: 2)
  - Mareš, Stanislav, 1972-1991 (Folder 51: 3)
  - Marlow, Frank, 1982-1993 (Folder 51: 4)
  - Mastník, Z., 1971, 1981-1984 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Maťátko, Jindřich, 1971-1981 (Folder 51: 6)
  - Matějka, Ladislav, 1980-1991 (Folder 51: 7)
  - Matuška, Waldemar, 1986-1987 (Folder 51: 8)
  - Mawhinney, Barry, and Robert G. McRae, 1989-1992 (Folder 51: 9)
  - Meců, Jára, 1981 (Folder 51: 10)
  - Medek, Ivan, 1978-1988 (Folder 51: 11)
  - Medjuck, Joseph, 1982-1993 (Folder 51: 12)
  - Meixnerová, Jiřina, 1978-1979 (Folder 51: 13)
  - Menzel, Jiří, 1980-1993 (Folder 51: 14)
  - Mercks, Kees, 1976 (Folder 51: 15)
  - Měšťan, Antonín, 1981-1990 (Folder 51: 16)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1976-1989 (Folder 51: 17)
  - Mlejnek, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Mlynárik, 1989 (Folder 52: 2)
  - Moc, Stanislav, 1981-1989 (Folder 52: 3)
  - Moníková, Libuše, 1987-1992 (Folder 52: 4)
  - Morava, Jiří, 1980-1990 (Folder 52: 5)
  - Moravec, F., 1990 (Folder 52: 6)
  - Morávková, Consuela, 1979 (Folder 52: 7)
  - Morris, Pavla, 1985-1994 (Folder 52: 8)
  - Munková, Alena, 1981, 1990-1991 (Folder 52: 9)
  - Murray, Irena, 1983-1990 (Folder 52: 10)
  - Nápravník, Milan, 1982-1989 (Folder 52: 11)
  - Navarová, Jarka, 1985 (Folder 52: 12)